splendia.com 2018-08-15

# Splendia - Privacy Policy

## Introduction of our Privacy and Personal Data Protection Policy

No surprise! We protect your information and you stay in control!  
We collect, use and share your information only as described in this policy. We are committed to protecting your privacy and the security of the personal data you entrust to us. You can update your profile and communication preferences at any time.

The confidentiality of your personal data being fundamental for us, this charter aims to explain how and for what purpose we use the information collected on our site Splendia.com. Below referred to as "Site", Splendia, a subsidiary of the Voyage Privé group, is responsible for processing your personal data collected on the splendia.com site and does everything possible to protect your privacy during your visits and reservations. Please read this privacy policy carefully. 

All personal data is collected and processed in accordance with European regulations, in particular General Data Protection Regulation No. 2016/679 (GDPR).

## The data we collect

### Data that you voluntarily transmit to us

At the time of registration, when you fill out a form to order a stay or change your member account information, Splendia collects personal information about you that you have agreed to provide to us. 

Personal information includes your email address and password, as well as information about you and your favourite passengers, including names, surnames, nationalities, dates of birth, telephone numbers, postal and email addresses, credit/debit card information or other payment information, notices, impressions and comments that you may leave on the Site about our services following a stay in one of our hotels, as well as communications exchanged with us or that you send us by mail, electronic messages, chat service, telephone calls or on social networks.

You can also send us data via Facebook or Google if you have expressly consented to the association of your Splendia member account with your Facebook user account or Google account at the time you register on the Site via Facebook Connect or Google's Login service. 

### Your browsing data

When you browse the Site, Splendia collects information related to your browsing session. Your browsing history on Splendia.com is thus collected: pages visited, time spent on the Site, web browser, type of devices, searches performed, preferred language, IP address of the device (stored in an anonymous format), screen resolution of the device, geographical location (country), mouse events (movements, clicks, location), key presses on the keyboard, date and time the pages of the Web site were consulted, reservations, contact request, opening of newsletters and click to our Web pages.  
Finally, like most sites today, Splendia uses cookies to store and access information.

## Processing your data

The personal data collected concerning you are subject to computer processing for the following purposes: 

### Processing your reservation

When you have placed an order on the Splendia.com Site, the personal data required to process your reservation are communicated to the Splendia service providers concerned by your stay (hotels, customer service, Hotel Business department, etc.). In addition, this data is also processed for customer relationship management and for Splendia - Voyage Privé's accounting needs (your invoices). 

### Sending communications relating to the service offered by Splendia

Splendia sends you several types of emails: 

\- Mails relating to your reservation: reservation confirmation, customer satisfaction questionnaire.   
\- Splendia Newsletter: You have the possibility to manage the frequency of sending in your account on the Site.  
\- Other personalized marketing emails: welcome emails, information emails, shopping cart abandonment, birthday emails, emails related to your activity cycle or inactivity, news related to Splendia and your member benefits.

An unsubscribe link is present on all communications sent, to give you the freedom to stop solicitations at any time.

### Statistical analyses

The data from your reservations are used to establish statistical analyses that enable us to manage Splendia's commercial activity. 

## Data protection

Splendia, a subsidiary of the Voyage Privé Group, implements all technical and organizational measures necessary to protect the personal data we hold against any access, modification, destruction or disclosure. To achieve this, we have implemented the following security measures in particular:

\- Our internal computer network, our servers and the Site are subject to technical measures that enable us to guarantee the highest degree of security for your personal data.  
\- We regularly have our security measures audited to ensure their effectiveness.  
\- Access to your personal data is strictly reserved to VPG Group employees and subcontractors, only for the necessary processing and for which you have given your consent.   
\- Any illegal intrusion into our database gives rise to an immediate alert and to the implementation of the necessary actions. 

## Is your data shared?

Given the nature of our activity and the use of this website, if you book a hotel room and in order to be able to access your request, Splendia will have to communicate your personal data to the chosen hotel as well as to the suppliers concerned by your booking in order to ensure the smooth processing of your order. In this context, your personal data may be transferred to a third country (outside the European Economic Area). If you book a stay in a country outside the EEA, the data required to process your booking will be transmitted to our suppliers.  
Some third countries may provide a lower level of protection for your personal data than that guaranteed by European Union law. In this case, Splendia undertakes to take all appropriate measures to ensure that your personal data is protected and processed in accordance with European Union law, in particular by implementing standard contractual clauses approved by the European Commission or contractual clauses previously authorised by the competent authority.

In addition, and in order to implement the personalization of your experience, we collaborate with service providers to whom we delegate the sending of communications or the collection and processing of data so that they can be analyzed and enable us to improve our service offering or personalize our communications. Within this framework, we only transmit to them the data necessary and sufficient for the execution of their mission. Our service providers are also contractually obliged to ensure that the personal data received are processed only within the defined framework and in compliance with regulations.

For the purpose of retargeting advertising by Splendia, we may also transmit some of your data to advertising partners or platforms, including the products you have viewed on our site, the details of your quotes or reservations (including destination, period of stay, number of people), the unique identifier of your mobile device and operating system, and in some cases your encrypted email address in a highly secure format. 

With the exception of the cases mentioned above, we will not communicate any data concerning you without your agreement, except in the case of a legal constraint (in the case for example of a judicial order or for purposes of prevention of fraud and other crimes).

## How long is your data kept?

The personal data that you communicate to us relating to your member account, your reservations, as well as your navigation data are kept for a period of 5 years from your last activity on the Site from the date of the end of your last stay. For accounting and tax purposes, some personal data may be retained for up to 10 years after your reservation.

At the end of this period, your Splendia member account will be automatically deactivated and you will have to create a new one if you wish to benefit from our services. 

## Security of your personal data

At Splendia, we follow strict security procedures regarding the retention and disclosure of your personal data, and to protect them from accidental loss, destruction or alteration. The data you provide to us is protected by SSL (Secure Socket Layer) protocol. SSL is the method used to encrypt credit card information and data so that it can be transferred securely over the Internet.

All payment data is transmitted via a secure connection (Secure Socket Layer-SSL) through an infrastructure secured by Thawte and stored in accordance with Payment Card Industry Data Security (PCI DSS) Service Provider Level 1 standards.

We may share your information with trusted third parties for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. We require all third parties to put in place appropriate technical and operational security measures to protect your personal data, in accordance with the data protection laws enshrined in French law and European Community law. 

## How to access your data or request deletion of your member account?

In accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation n°2016/679, you have the right to request access to your personal data, to rectify or delete them, to limit the processing carried out, to oppose the processing and the portability of your data. For that you can send your request by email to info@splendia.com or use our online form available at the following address: https://www.splendia.com/en/customer-care#email

If you wish to delete your Splendia member account, go to the "Contact us" section and send us an email specifying in the subject "Delete account". 

Because your privacy is an integral part of our culture at Splendia, we use a combination of travel industry standard methods to protect your data. In accordance with the law, you have the right in certain circumstances to :

\- Request information about whether we have personal information about you and, if so, what that information is and why we keep/use it.  
\- Request access to your personal information (commonly called "request access to his personal data"). This request allows you to receive a copy of the personal information we hold about you and to verify that we are legally processing that data.  
\- Request correction of the personal information we have about you. This allows you to correct any incomplete or inaccurate information we have about you.  
\- Request the deletion of your personal information. This allows you to ask us to delete or remove any personal information that we no longer have a reason to process. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal information when you have exercised your right to object to the processing of your data (see below).  
\- You object to the processing of your personal information if we have a legitimate interest (or the interest of a third party) in doing so and if there is a reason related to your particular situation that you wish to object to the processing. You also have the right to object if we process your personal information for direct marketing purposes.  
\- Oppose automated individual decision-making, including profiling, so that we do not make automated decisions using your personal information or profiling.  
\- Request the limitation of the processing of your personal information. This allows you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal information, for example if you wish to establish the accuracy or the reason for the data processing.  
\- Request the transfer of your personal information for your benefit or for the benefit of another data controller in an electronic and structured format (right to data portability). This allows you to recover and transfer your data in an electronically usable format.  
\- Withdraw your consent. Where you have consented to the collection, processing and transfer of your personal information for a particular purpose, you have the right to withdraw your consent to such data processing at any time. Once we receive notification of withdrawal of your consent, we will no longer process your information for the purpose(s) for which you gave your consent, unless we have a legitimate reason to do so.

If you wish to exercise any of these rights, please send an e-mail to our Data Protection Officer (DPO) at www.splendia.com/en/customer-care#email or contact our DPO by post at the address Voyage Privé 684 avenue du Club Hippique - 13 090 Aix-en-Provence - France or complete an online application form available using the following link: https://www.splendia.com/en/customer-care#email

We may ask you for specific information to help us confirm your identity and ensure that your right of access to this information is respected (or for the exercise of any other of your rights). This is a security measure to ensure that your personal information is not disclosed to anyone who is not authorized to view it.

You also have the possibility to lodge a complaint with the authoritative inspection body in your country of residence (e.g. CNIL in France, Agencia Espanola de Protección de Datos in Spain, ICA in the United Kingdom, Garante per la protezione dei dati personali in Italy and the Federal Commissioner for Data Protection and Freedom of Information in Germany).

## Cookie Policy and tracking on the site

Splendia's cookie policy informs you about the operation and purpose of the cookies used by Splendia and how to manage your choices with respect to these cookies. 

### What is a cookie?

A cookie is a piece of data that is stored on a computer, tablet or mobile device when you surf the Internet. Cookies allow the website to recognize your browser. They are mainly used to remember your choices and preferences. They do not cause any damage to your device. For example, they allow you to customize the content you view. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, however, you obviously have the option to disable or prevent the placement of these cookies (see the "help" section of your web browser to set these functions). Please note that such an operation may cause the site to malfunction.

### What types of cookies are used by Splendia?

Technical cookies: are essential to ensure the proper functioning of our service.   
Analytical cookies: are useful for tracking how you use and navigate the site. The data we collect mainly includes the pages you visit, open and close, the type of browser and media you use, as well as information such as the number of clicks made on a given page. This collected data remains anonymous and does not reveal your identity.   
Advertising cookies: are used to display Splendia advertisements on other sites. This is called "retargeting". It is built on the basis of the navigation information collected and the filters used during your searches on our site. We use tracking software to monitor customer traffic patterns and site usage to help us develop website design and layout. This software does not allow us to capture passengers' personal information.

### How does it work on Splendia?

When you visit Splendia.com, you authorize us, via a consent cookie, to collect data about your browsing. This data is then used to offer you the best hotels and destinations that can meet your expectations either on the site or by sending newsletters. These cookies may be stored by us and by third parties for measurement tools and advertising retargeting campaigns. Information from these cookies can be stored for up to 5 years. As a reminder, you can delete your cookies at any time (consult the "help" section of your Internet browser to set these functions). Please note: if you choose to decline certain cookies, you will not be able to use certain features of our site. Similarly, if you refuse certain advertising cookies, it does not mean that you will no longer see online advertisements. This will simply result in ads that are no longer based on your preferences and user behavior, and therefore less relevant to you.

### How to manage your cookie choices?

You can enable or disable cookies on your device using the settings in your Internet browser. The configuration of these settings varies from browser to browser. You can usually find detailed instructions in your browser's Help menu or by following the links below:

For Internet Explorer™ : http://windows.microsoft.com/fr-FR/windows-vista/Block-or-allow-cookies   
For Safari™ : http://support.apple.com/   
For Chrome™ : http://support.google.com/chrome/bin/answer.py?hl=en&hlrm=en&answer=95647   
For Firefox™ : http://support.mozilla.org/fr/kb/Activer%20and%20d%C3%A9sactiver%20les%20cookies   
For Opera™ : http://help.opera.com/Windows/10.20/fr/cookies.html

You can also manage your choices through the Youronlinechoices site, proposed by digital advertising professionals grouped within the European association EDAA (European Digital Advertising Alliance) and managed in France by the Interactive Advertising Bureau (IAB) France : http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices  
For more information about cookies and how to stop cookies visit the following website: http://www.allaboutcookies.org.

## Hyperlinks to third party websites

We are not responsible for the privacy policies and practices of other websites even if you have accessed them via hypertext links on our own site. In addition, if you are referred to our site through a third party site, we are not responsible for the privacy practices of the owners or operators of that third party site.   
We recommend that you carefully review the privacy policies of all sites you visit and contact their owners or operators if you have any problems or questions.

## Who are we and how can you contact us?

Splendia is a subsidiary of the Voyage Privé group, a simplified joint stock company with a capital of 983,691.39 euros - whose registered office is located at 684 avenue du Club Hippique - 13,090 Aix-en-Provence - registered with the RCS d'Aix-en-Provence under number 479 345 043. 

Voyage Privé is responsible for processing all information we collect from you. Splendia's offices are located in Barcelona, Spain at Passeig de Gracia, 55. 

Telephone: 0892 426 425   
Email: info@splendia.com  
Contact details of the Data Protection Officer: dpo@voyageprive.com 

## Changes of the Privacy Policy

Our privacy policy may change from time to time and changes to it will be notified to you by email or by a notice on our Splendia.com website.

Last update date: May 25, 2018
